(Watch on KonFlix.vip)
If you want to get her to study,
you'll be better off throwing away
the textbooks altogether.
Excuse me?
While you're here,
only do things that you think are fun.
What's with that guy?
He's got a super naive mindset,
but is he all right?
Tatsuki.
‎PREVIOUSLY ON ‎TATSUKI: TOO KIND FOR SCHOOL
I don't
want to go to school.
I think Ayaka couldn't
bring herself to express her true feelings
because her mother is so important to her.
I was always
a little too relieved whenever…
you went to school, huh?
I'm sorry.
-Hello?
-Tatsuki.
Sora jumped.
What?
How's Sora?
Is he in there?
Wait.
It's all right.
-But he jumped--
-He's not in a critical condition.
So just leave.
Now.
Tatsuki.
He's sleeping.
What? What is it?
It's time for the meeting.
-Meeting?
-Yeah.
Okay.
All right,
let's begin this week's meeting.
-Okay.
First up, Tuesday.
There's a plan to go see the movie Mario,
but is everyone done signing up?
-I'll go too.
-Okay.
-I'll sign up too.
-Let's watch a romantic comedy.
-Romantic comedy?
-I have an idea for the next
-training camp.
-Training camp?
I want to eat paella this week.
-Paella?
-Yes, paella.
Paella!
Hold on, we're still discussing the movie.
We'll talk about the paella later.
We hold a meeting like this every week
to decide on various plans.
Do I need to take charge or anything?
No need.
We just need to watch over them.
Everything works out all right?
They won't follow plans made by adults,
but they'll stick to the ones
they decided on themselves.
-I see.
-Next.
What's the plan for Thursday's
Activity Day at the community center?
-Tag.
-Dodgeball.
-Tag?
-Basketball!
-Yeah, basketball.
-Paella.
-Dodgeball?
-Enough with the paella.
-Yeah, I want to do that too.
-Okay, let's vote.
Who wants to play tag?
-Me.
-Who wants to play basketball?
-What?
Hold on, guys.
You can only vote once.
We're not doing that.
-I vote for dodgeball.
-I want to eat paella.
-Who wants to do trampoline?
-I think it's a new applicant.
All right.
Mr. Tatsuki.
Hello.
-Nice to meet you.
Say hello.
Hello, I'm Saku Sugitani.
Hello.
-Please sit.
-Thank you.
He's currently a fifth grader
in elementary school,
but starting around mid-April,
he started taking days off of school.
After the long holiday break,
he told me he doesn't want to go back.
Did something happen at school?
Not really.
He doesn't seem to be having
any problems with his friends.
You just don't want to go to school?
It's a drag.
A drag, huh.
Yeah, school is such a drag.
I totally get it.
-Mr. Tatsuki.
-What?
I happened to learn about Yukanai online.
I thought that letting children
be independent and free
might be the right approach
for my son right now.
Yes, everyone here is certainly
doing what they want.
When I asked him about it,
he said he wanted to come.
I see.
Do you play soccer?
You like sports in general, right?
Kind of…
-Yeah.
-I see.
He's pretty good with his studies too.
Whoa, no way.
You're definitely popular, huh?
-You are, huh?
-Mr. Tatsuki.
-What?
-Let's not say that.
-Why? He's so impressive.
-But still…
-There's no way he's not popular.
-That's not the issue.
Your turn to serve.
-Where did it go?
-Are you serious?
Let's play soccer.
Yeah.
We're going to play soccer now,
wanna join us?
It'll be out in the yard.
I'm okay right now.
Okay.
Come join us when you feel like it.
-Let's go.
-Yeah.
-Nice, nice.
-Let's go.
-Yeah.
You can use anything here
however you like.
Hey, let's play Bomb Busters.
Okay.
Let's play next time.
Gaku, let's play this.
What?
What happened?
-I'm sorry.
-What happened?
I'm sorry.
-Are you all right?
-Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
-Were you replacing the books?
-Yeah.
Professor Mikumo
brought us a bunch of old books
the other day.
Do you like history?
No…
I don't know much about history.
Are there any Sengoku warlords you like?
-Nobunaga.
-Oh, I know a little about him.
Who's this man?
TALES OF THE STRONGEST SENGOKU WARLORDS
Kuroda Kanbei.
Wow, you really know a lot!
You can take that home.
-Really?
-Yeah.
I'm sure no one else will read it.
I've got a good idea.
-All right.
-What are you doing?
I'm making a collage.
-A collage?
-Yup.
You just cut out images that you like
and paste them together.
By the way, those are collages
made by another student.
Wow.
Try it out.
Which one should I choose?
SOCCER MANIA
Hey, can you help me reach the top of
-the bookshelf--
-Once you cut that out, paste it on here.
-Um…
-How?
-However you want to.
-Can you hear me?
It's too high, and I can't reach it so…
-Ms. Shizuku.
-I'll do this one.
Can you bring more old magazines?
Go get them yourself.
What was that for?
-Mr. Tatsuki.
-Just call me Tatsuki.
-You have to be nicer to women.
-What?
Oh, you mean about Ms. Shizuku?
Yeah. She was mad.
What? She was mad?
Really?
You're so oblivious.
I get that a lot.
BATTLE OF KANEGASAKI
All done.
It turned out so powerful.
What's happening in this scene?
They're fighting.
But they're getting pushed back
by the enemy.
I see.
Who's this?
-Nobunaga.
-I thought so.
He's so strong and amazing.
Yeah, he's amazing.
Hey, Tatsuki.
Don't tell anyone
that I'm a history buff, okay?
Okay.
As for Thursday's Activity Day,
we couldn't pick just one thing,
so we'll be doing everything.
It'll be like Sports Day.
Then let's play tug-of-war too.
I just got this rope. Look!
No way!
Where did you get that?
Did you get it from a shrine?
I guess it was being used
at the local festival,
but it's too old now.
-Then let's do tug-of-war too.
-Okay.
-Pull this, Soya.
Come on.
‎Wow.
‎-Bye Professor.
‎-Bye
Hey there.
Hey.
-A collage?
-Yes.
A Sengoku warlord and soccer players.
It's an interesting combination, isn't it?
Who made this collage?
He's a boy in fifth grade.
He seems to be good at studies and sports,
and has friends too.
But he refuses to go to school, right?
-Yes.
-Why?
-He said it's a drag.
-A drag?
Does that mean he finds it tiring?
No, how can I explain it…?
Is it that he can't sum up
the energy to go?
I think he considers it a hassle.
-I see.
-What do you think about this?
There's just one guy who's running away.
You're right.
The boss has a really
intimidating presence, doesn't he?
Does it represent someone?
If it's not a friend,
maybe
a teacher, for example?
That's a possibility.
Kids sometimes stop going to school
when they don't get along with teachers.
Yeah.
Saku goes to Nishiogi Elementary School,
so I'll try to find something out tomorrow
when I go to submit
the academic progress report.
You sure love schools, huh.
It's not that I love it or anything.
I hope you don't complicate things more.
Then you want to just let things be?
Tatsuki, you should go with her.
-Oh, I can't tomorrow…
-You have plans?
I have to catch
a different colored Pikachu.
What?
This is more important than that!
I guess you can't cancel that.
Are you serious?
NISHIOGI ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
I can't think of the reason why either.
Sugitani is a very popular
and outgoing student in our class.
He started missing school
around mid-April, right?
At first it was just Mondays.
Then Mondays and Wednesdays.
It gradually kept increasing.
I see.
Oh, sorry,
-I have to practice for Sports Day.
-Sorry.
-Thank you.
-No problem.
CLASS SCHEDULE
Mondays and Wednesdays.
MONDAY - PE
WEDNESDAY
PE
All right, stop. One, two.
Hey, you stepped out of line.
Let's do it one more time.
Step in place.
It looks like Sports Day is in two weeks.
I wonder if there's any point
in practicing marching.
It's satisfying to watch
when they're in sync, isn't it?
-One, two.
-You think so?
I wonder if Saku
didn't like the Sports Day practice.
-But he's good at all sports, right?
-Yes.
In that case, Sports Day is actually
a great opportunity for him to shine.
But he started skipping school on days
when they had PE,
and when the Sports Day practices began.
Step in place.
Doesn't that teacher
-kind of remind you of Nobunaga?
-One, two.
One, two! Hey, you're doing it
the wrong way!
One, two.
Keep looking at everyone around you!
-Oh yes…
-One, two!
Excuse me. Sorry to bother you
when you're so busy.
I'm Aomine from
the alternative school, Yukanai.
-I'm Tatsuki.
-How can I help you?
I'd like to ask you a few questions
about Saku Sugitani.
I'm very worried about Sugitani too.
How is he doing at your school?
Oh, he's doing well.
I'm so glad.
He was always so cheerful.
-Thank you.
Good day.
He ended up being a nice guy, huh?
You shouldn't have judged
a book by its cover.
Hey, you thought he was scary too,
didn't you?
No, I did not.
So unfair.
I was absolutely convinced that
the Sports Day practice was the issue.
I think you've got it right.
You think so too?
I got this.
-The program for Sports Day?
-Yup.
SPORTS DAY
Which one was Saku planning
to participate in?
He was chosen for the fifth-grade events,
and also as a runner for the relay team.
I see.
SPORTS DAY
All right!
-Damn it.
-He's so good.
Saku, you're so good.
What's the trick?
Don't just move your arm,
but put your weight into it like this.
-You're good at everything, Saku.
-Kind of.
All right everyone.
Let's start cleaning up.
-Okay.
-All right!
-Good job.
-I did it.
-You're a genius.
I did it.
Let's clean up.
-No, one more time.
-Clean it up.
Let's play this other game.
-What?
-Let's play this game.
I want to play Jenga.
What about Dominion?
Let's all clean up.
Everyone please take
the Activity Day flyer
when you leave.
-Okay.
-Is Tatsuki going too?
Yeah. You'll be going too, right?
Yeah, I'm looking forward to it.
Take this home with you.
Thank you.
-Oh, wow, how exciting.
-Take this home with you.
-Thanks.
-Take care.
-Bye.
-Go Red!
-Game start!
‎-Gaku!
‎-Tatsuki!
Nice pass!
Go, go!
Start.
‎We can do it.
Make sure you score.
-You can do it, Tatsuki.
-Go.
Go!
Don't get too depressed about it.
Saku.
You're not going to dance?
If they try to go into defense here,
then that will cause…
-Tatsuki.
-Yeah?
Was it okay for you to leave?
The truth is,
I'm not very good at ball games.
My penalty kick was terrible, huh?
Yeah.
I lost motivation after that.
If I did something that embarrassing
-I wouldn't be able to live.
-Hey.
I'm not like you who can do everything.
I can't dance.
I see.
I can't do the dance
for Sports Day.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four, five, six…
I can never remember the steps.
Once I fall out of sync,
I can't keep up anymore.
I just keep feeling
more and more pathetic.
I see.
That's tough.
Just ask to be removed from the dance.
What?
No need to force yourself to do it.
Everyone has to participate in the dance.
But you still want to compete
in the other events, right?
Isn't it frustrating to have to sit
everything out just for that?
If you want to run away,
it's okay to do so.
I just ran away too.
But…
I can't admit to everyone now
that I'm bad at dancing.
Because you're known for
being good at everything?
Yeah.
What do you want to do?
You can choose to do
whatever you want, Saku.
I don't want…
to do the dance.
I went to his school.
They said Saku doesn't have
to participate in the dance.
Um… I actually went out of my way
to visit his school
after Activity Day ended.
Thanks.
I'm glad you can benefit
from my love for school.
What?
I'm sure schools love you too,
Ms. Shizuku.
Forget it.
Thank you. I'll relay the news to Saku.
Thank you. Bye.
Good morning.
Hey, Saku.
Saku is here. Let's play Ruler Wars.
-Yeah, let's.
-Are you better now?
Yup. I made a complete recovery!
Right, left, hop, hop, hop.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
Hey, did you make your mask?
-A mask?
-All right, let's take a break.
-No…
-Make sure to stay hydrated.
I'm going to the restroom.
Hey Saku. Why are you just watching?
Just because…
I'm going to the restroom.
Left, right, left, hop…
YUKANAI
NOW ACCEPTING NEW STUDENTS!
Yes, Saku is here, so please don't worry.
Yes. Goodbye.
-Was that his school?
-Yeah,
it seems like he suddenly left
during PE.
I see.
You left school without telling anyone?
It's boring to just watch.
Yeah, it's boring, huh?
But if you leave without a word,
everyone will worry.
I'm sorry.
Want to make another collage?
-I have to return the books I borrowed.
-What?
Oh, you can have those old books.
But I read them all.
LET'S MAKE A MASK FOR THE DANCE!
Apparently, it's a mask for the dance.
I don't need that.
Want to make it?
What?
-He sat out on practice, but left mid-way?
-Yes.
But we're not really sure why.
Maybe he started hating himself
for running away.
That's a possibility too.
He tends to be a perfectionist.
Since I used to work
as a middle school teacher,
I tend to think that
you have to challenge all things,
even if it's something you're not
particularly good at.
Yes.
I think overcoming difficulties
is also a part of education.
But if it's going to break their spirit,
then it's better
not to push them too hard.
It's tough, isn't it?
-Done.
-Let me see.
Ta-da. Guess who this is.
A hint. He's a soccer player.
I wonder who it is.
Ramos.
-Who is that?
-You don't know Ramos?
Seriously? Okay then…
Is it Messi?
-Bingo.
-Yes.
Let's see yours.
Ta-da.
It looks just like you.
Right?
Let's draw on the other side too.
-The other side?
-Yeah.
For the other side…
Let's draw a secret side of us,
one we usually never show anyone.
Are you crying?
You usually don't want anyone
to see you crying, right?
Is that a Sengoku warlord?
Nobunaga?
Bingo.
Why did you choose Nobunaga?
I wonder why.
Oh, because it's a secret
that you're a history buff?
Maybe that's it.
After all, it doesn't fit my image.
Both the front and back turned out great.
Saku, let's head home.
It's okay. I'll clean up. You can go.
-Thanks.
-Sure.
-Tatsuki.
-Yeah?
I'm going
to try the dance after all.
What?
I'll practice on my own
and learn the dance by Sports Day.
Okay.
-A mask?
-Yeah.
He made the mask
that's going to be used for the dance,
but it seems
that really got him motivated.
What kind of a mask was it?
Messi is on the front,
and Nobunaga is on the back.
Apparently, Saku admires both of them.
I see.
This is Mr. Tatsuki's mask.
Don't bring that out…
Oh? Why is he crying?
Well,
it's a face I don't want to show others.
I see.
When doing art therapy,
people create pieces
that distinguish between
their outward self and the self
they wish to keep hidden deep inside.
Huh?
Mr. Tatsuki,
-what are you keeping hidden inside?
-Stop that.
By the way,
can you stop calling me "Mr." please?
It seems like
art therapy really does work, doesn't it?
Saku seems to have been motivated.
What do you think?
But perhaps
even he himself doesn't realize
the true feelings he has
deep within his heart.
I see.
If I recall correctly, he used Nobunaga
in that collage the other day too.
I was under the impression
that he was a frightening figure to Saku,
but he actually seems to like him.
In that case, you ought to delve deeper
into the thing that he likes.
You just might discover something new.
Okay.
Right, left, hop, hop, hop.
Ready? Let's start.
Five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four…
Three, four, five, six…
Let's do it again.
YUKANAI
Good morning, Saku.
Where's Tatsuki?
-I'll go call him.
-No…
It's okay.
What're you doing?
I'm not very good with history,
so I tried to study by putting myself
in Nobunaga’s shoes. I splurged on this.
You bought it?
By the way, Lord, what is the matter?
We have
a full dance rehearsal
this afternoon, but…
Sports Day is coming up, huh?
I'm scared.
You practiced, right?
But
I've only practiced on my own.
It might be hard
to dance along with everyone, huh?
That's what scares me.
Do you want to sit out?
You can run away if you want.
But that just doesn't fit my image.
I’m supposed to be strong
and able to do anything.
Why?
If I can't do it,
everyone will be disappointed in me.
I'll look lame too.
That's just not who I am.
That's why
you have to be strong like Nobunaga?
Yeah.
But apparently,
Nobunaga actually ran away
from a battle once.
This image of Nobunaga
that you pasted on here,
was taken from an illustration
of the Battle of Kanegasaki, huh?
BATTLE OF KANEGASAKI
I figured that out yesterday
after studying.
I didn't even notice that.
The Battle of Kanegasaki is referred to as
the "battle of the forced retreat",
isn't it?
In 1570,
Nobunaga laid siege to Kanegasaki Castle,
but after being betrayed by Azai Nagamasa,
he had to flee in order to survive.
What do you think
of Nobunaga for retreating? Was he lame?
If it was me
I'd be a bit embarrassed.
I see.
But
I don't think
he's lame.
It's kind of cool
how he bares all his weaknesses, huh?
Saku, you can become
Nobunaga too.
Saku, let's play soccer.
-Let's go.
-Let's play.
Wait.
Sorry.
Can you help me practice the dance?
I couldn't get all the moves
by watching the video.
Sure.
He took days off.
Yeah, so we'll help you.
Thanks.
Right, left,
down, and tap.
Get up.
Touch and turn. Right…
-Sorry, one more time.
-Sure.
Let's review the previous moves too.
What's the matter?
Hey,
what do you think of me
being a bad dancer?
Why this all of a sudden?
I have no sense of rhythm,
and I'm stiff…
Isn't that lame?
Not really.
But I'm known as someone
who can do anything.
Huh?
-Is that right?
-What?
We don't think you're perfect or anything.
Yeah.
-What?
-Yeah,
because you can be pretty kooky.
Yeah, totally.
No way. Kooky? Me?
For example,
when it was music class,
you went to the home economics room.
First of all, the fact
that you think you're perfect…
Means you're kooky.
Seriously?
That's how I was coming across
to everyone?
But you guys haven't figured out
that I'm a history buff, right?
-Who cares if everyone knows?
-Yeah.
By the way,
let's practice, or you'll really be lame.
Sorry, can we start from the top again?
Okay.
-Ready?
-Yeah.
Let's start.
One, two, three, four…
Walk in place. Begin.
One, two.
Next up is a dance performance
by the fifth graders.
It's called, "Dancing
As My Character."
-Where is he?
-I see him.
Where? Point to him.
-Oh, there he is.
-That's him.
Good luck.
Oh.
Hello.
-Hello.
-Saku is over there.
-Oh, I see him. Thank you.
-He's Messi.
One, two.
Saku!
You can do it!
Tatsuki.
‎All right.
Good job!
Tatsuki.
You came.
Good job.
I messed up.
But it was very you, Saku.
What's that supposed to mean?
You were cool,
but also endearing.
That's not my image.
But I'll go with a new image from now on.
But don't get tied down by your image.
It's fine for you to be yourself.
But you're maintaining your image too.
What?
On the surface, you're always smiling
but inside, there's darkness, right?
I don't have a hidden side.
There's definitely darkness to you.
-You think so?
-Yeah.
No need to force a smile
when you're feeling down.
What the hell?
Can I go visit you again?
Of course.
Bye.
-See you.
-Bye.
Sora, staying holed up like that
isn't going to solve anything, is it?
Are you listening?
-Sora.
-That's enough.
-Go to work.
-Sora, open the door.
-Come out here.
-No.
Stop it. That's enough. Just stop it.
Sora!
PREVIEW OF THE NEXT EPISODE
THIS DRAMA IS FICTION
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita